ARMENAK PETROSYAN, PH.D.

apetrosyan3@gatech.edu owww.petrosyan.page

SUMMARY

My research is primarily in Applied Harmonic Analysis and Machine Learning. I study problems related to recovery of systems of signals under sparse or structural assumptions, and approximation and representation capabilities of artificial neural networks.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

· Hale Visiting Assistant Professor

Aug 2020 - Present

School of Mathematics

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, USA

Mentor: Prof. Christopher Heil

· Postdoctoral Research Associate

Aug 2017 - Jul 2020

Computer Science and Mathematics Division Oak Ridge National Laboratory, TN, USA

Mentor: Prof. Clayton Webster

FORMAL EDUCATION

· PhD in Mathematics

Aug 2012 - Aug 2017

Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN, USA

PhD advisor: Prof. Akram Aldroubi

· Master's degree in Mathematics

Sep 2010 - May 2012

Yerevan State University, Armenia Master's advisor: Prof. Artur Sahakian

Master's advisor. I for. Artur Sanakian

· Bachelor's degree in Mathematics

Sep 2006 - May 2010

Yerevan State University, Armenia

PUBLICATIONS

· A. Petrosyan, K. Pieper, and H. Tran

A proximal Lagrange-function Gradient method for rank-aware joint sparse regularization. In preperation

· A. Aldroubi, V. Baily, I. Krishtal, and A, Petrosyan

Dynamical sampling on networks.

In preperation

· K. Pieper and A. Petrosyan

Non-convex penalization for shallow neural networks.

arXiv:2004.11515, 2021

· A. Aldroubi, C. Cabrelli, U. Molter, and A. Petrosyan

Local-to-global frames and applications to dynamical sampling problem.

Excursions in Harmonic Analysis, Volume 6, pp. 211-220. Birkhäuser, Cham, 2021

· K. Hamm, B. Hayes, and A. Petrosyan

An operator theoretic approach to the convergence of rearranged Fourier series. Journal d'Analyse Mathématique, 143(2), pp.503-534, 2021

· A. Dereventsov, A. Petrosyan, and C. Webster

Neural network integral representations with the ReLU activation function.

Mathematical and Scientific Machine Learning, pp. 128-143. PMLR, 2020.

· K. Hamm, B. Hayes, and A. Petrosyan

Rearranged Fourier Series and Generalizations to Non-Commutative Groups.

13th International Conference on Sampling Theory and Applications (SampTA), pp. 1-4. IEEE, 2019.

· A. Aldroubi, L. Huang, A. Petrosyan

Frames induced by the action of continuous powers of an operator.

Journal of Mathematical Analysis and Applications, 478(2), 1059-1084, 2019

· A. Petrosyan, H. Tran, and C. Webster

Reconstruction of jointly sparse vectors via manifold optimization.

Applied Numerical Mathematics, 144, p. 140-150, 2019

· A. Aldroubi, C. Cabrelli, A. F. Cakmak, U. Molter, and A. Petrosyan

Iterative actions of normal operators.

Journal of Functional Analysis, 272(3), p. 1121-1146, 2017

· A. Aldroubi and A. Petrosyan

Dynamical sampling and systems from iterative actions of operators

Frames and Other Bases in Abstract and Function Spaces, pp. 15-26. Birkhäuser, Cham, 2017.

· R. Aceska, A. Aldroubi, J. Davis, and A. Petrosyan

Dynamical sampling in shift-invariant spaces

AMS Contemporary Mathematics (CONM) book series, p. 139-148, 2013

GRANTS AND AWARDS

- · Georgia Tech-ORNL seed grant (\$4000).
- · Member of the Grand Prize winner team for ORNL SNS Neutral Scattering Ugly Data challenge competition. Details can be found at https://datadays.pages.ornl.gov/SNS/.

CONFERENCE AND SESSION ORGANIZATION

- · Focus program on Data Science, Approximation Theory, and Harmonic Analysis co-organized with Akram Aldroubi, Keaton Hamm and Javad Mashreghi, Fields Institute, 2022
- · Fast Algorithms, Sparsity and Approximation, Part I-III

 16th International Conferences on Approximation Theory
 co-organized with with Bosu Choi and Mark Iwen, University of Tennessee at Knoxville, September 21-22,
 2019
- Reduced and Parametric Methods for Function Approximations
 16th International Conferences on Approximation Theoryco-organized with with Anton Dereventsov, Vanderbilt University, TN, May 19, 2019

RECENT PRESENTATIONS

· CodEx Seminar

Online, September 7, 2021

Title: "Integral neural networks with weight penalization."

· Mathematical and Scientific Machine Learning (MSML 2020),

Princeton University (held online), July 21, 2020.

Title: "Integral neural networks with the ReLU activation function."

· Applied Mathematics Seminar,

University of California, Los Angeles, March 4, 2020.

Title: "Neural network integral representations and sparse networks."

· Conference on Computational Mathematics and Applications,

University of Nevada, Las Vegas, October 25 - 27, 2019.

Title: "Neural network integral representations."

· SIAM SEAS 2019 Annual Meeting,

University of Tennessee, Knoxville, September 20-22, 2019.

Title: "Neural network integral representations on the sphere for the ReLU activation function."

· 13th SampTA (Sampling Theory and Applications),

University of Bordeaux, France, July 8-12, 2019.

Title: "Rearranged Fourier Series and Generalizations to Non-commutative Groups."

· Signal Processing with Adaptive Sparse Structured Representations (SPARS) workshop,

ENSEEIHT, Toulouse, France, July 1-4, 2019.

Title: "Joint sparse recovery through manifold optimization."

· 16th International Conferences on Approximation Theory,

Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN, May 19-22, 2019.

Title: "Rearranged Fourier Series and Generalizations to Non-commutative Groups."

· AMS Fall Western Sectional Meeting,

San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA, October 27-28, 2018.

Title: "Joint sparse recovery through manifold optimization."

· 7th International Conference on Computational Harmonic Analysis and 60th Birthday Workshop for Akram Aldroubi.

Aldroubi,

Nashville TN, May 14-19, 2018.

Title: "Joint sparse recovery through manifold optimization."

· BIRS Numerical Analysis and Approximation Theory meets Data Science,

Banff, Canada, April 22-28, 2018.

Title: "Joint sparse recovery through manifold optimization."

TEACHING

· Statistical Theory

Georgia Institute of technology

Spring 2022.

· Discrete Mathematics and Graph Theory Georgia Institute of technology Fall 2021.

· Probability and Statistics Georgia Institute of technology Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Summer 2021.